It was almost two years later when I realized what this person should be called. I was speaking at the University of Michigan to the MBA candidates, talking about the lessons that I had learned after my three short years on Wall Street, and then it came to me. I said, "Oh, this person that is carrying your interest, or as I like to say, carrying your paper into the room, this person who is spending their valuable political and social capital on you,
Fue casi dos años después cuando me di cuenta de cómo debía llamarse esa persona. Estaba dando una charla en la Universidad de Michigan a los candidatos a MBA, hablando sobre lo que había aprendido después de mi tres cortos años en Wall Street, y de repente caí. Dije: "Oh, esta persona que vela por sus intereses, o como a mí me gusta decir, que lleva tu papel a la sala, esta persona que está gastando su valioso capital político y social en uno,
this person who is going to pound the table on your behalf, this is a sponsor. This is a sponsor." And then I said to myself, "Well, how do you get a sponsor? And frankly, why do you need one?" Well, you need a sponsor, frankly, because as you can see, there's not one evaluative process that I can think of, whether it's in academia, health care, financial services, not one that does not have a human element. So that means it has that measure of subjectivity. There is a measure of subjectivity in who is presenting your case. There is a measure of subjectivity in what they say and how they interpret any objective data that you might have. There is a measure of subjectivity in how they say what they're going to say to influence the outcome. So therefore, you need to make sure that that person who is speaking, that sponsor, has your best interests at heart and has the power to get it, whatever it is for you, to get it done behind closed doors. Now, I'm asked all the time, "How do you get one?" Well, frankly, nirvana is when someone sees you in an environment and decides, "I'm going to make it happen for you. I'm going to make sure that you are successful." But for many of us in this room, we know it doesn't really happen that way. So let me introduce this concept of currency and talk to you about how it impacts your ability to get a sponsor. There are two types of currency in any environment: performance currency and relationship currency. And performance currency is the currency that is generated by your delivering that which was asked of you and a little bit extra. Every time you deliver upon an assignment above people's expectations, you generate performance currency. It works exactly like the stock market. Any time a company says to the street that they will deliver 25 cents a share and that company delivers 40 cents a share, that stock goes up, and so will yours. Performance currency is valuable for three reasons. Number one, it will get you noticed. It will create a reputation for you. Number two, it will also get you paid and promoted very early on in your career and very early on in any environment. And number three, it may attract a sponsor. Why? Because strong performance currency raises your level of visibility in the environment, as I said earlier, such that a sponsor may be attracted to you. Why? Because everybody loves a star. But if you find yourself in a situation where you don't have a sponsor, here's the good news. Remember that you can exercise your power and ask for one. But here's where the other currency is now most important. That is the relationship currency,
esa persona que va a golpear la mesa en tu defensa es un promotor. Es un promotor". Y luego me dije a mí misma: "Vale, ¿cómo se obtiene un promotor? Y sinceramente, ¿para qué se necesita uno?". Pues sinceramente, se necesita un promotor porque como pueden ver, que yo sepa no hay un solo proceso evaluativo, ya sea en el ámbito académico, en el sanitario o en servicios financieros, no hay ni uno que no tenga un elemento humano. Eso significa que tiene la medida de la subjetividad. Hay una medida de subjetividad en quién presenta su caso. Hay una medida de subjetividad en lo que dicen y en cómo interpretan cualquier dato objetivo que uno pueda tener. Hay una medida de subjetividad en cómo dicen lo que van a decir para influenciar el resultado. Así que tienen que asegurarse de que la persona que va a hablar, ese promotor, de verdad desee su mayor beneficio y tenga el poder de conseguirlo, sea lo que sea para uno, para hacerlo a puerta cerrada. Constantemente me preguntan: "¿Cómo consigues uno?" La verdad, el nirvana es cuando alguien te ve en un entorno y decide "voy a hacer que le suceda. Voy a asegurarme de que tenga éxito". Pero muchos de nosotros en esa sala sabemos que en realidad no funciona así. Así que déjenme presentarles el concepto de beneplácito y hablarles sobre cómo afecta a su capacidad de conseguir un promotor. Hay dos tipos de beneplácito en cualquier entorno: beneplácito de rendimiento y beneplácito de relaciones. El beneplácito del rendimiento es el beneplácito que se genera cuando entregan lo que se les han pedido y un poquito más. Cada vez que entregan un encargo por encima de las expectativas de la gente generan beneplácito de rendimiento. Funciona igual que el mercado de valores. Cada vez que una empresa dice al público que darán 25 centavos por acción y esa empresa da 40 centavos por acción esas acciones suben, y las suyas también. El beneplácito de rendimiento es valioso por tres motivos. Número uno, hará que se fijen en Uds. Les creará una reputación. Número dos, también hará que les paguen y los asciendan muy pronto en su trabajo y muy pronto en cualquier entorno. Y número tres, puede atraer a algún promotor. ¿Por qué? Porque un beneplácito de fuerte rendimiento aumenta su nivel de visibilidad en ese entorno, como he dicho antes, de manera que un promotor puede sentirse atraído por Uds. ¿Por qué? Porque todo el mundo adora a una estrella. Pero si se encuentran en una situación en la que no tienen un promotor tengo buenas noticias. Recuerden que pueden ejercer su poder y pedir uno. Pero aquí es donde el otro beneplácito es más importante. El beneplácito en las relaciones,
and relationship currency is the currency that is generated by the investments that you make in the people in your environment, the investments that you make in the people in your environment. You cannot ask someone to use their hard-earned personal influential currency on your behalf if you've never had any interaction with them. It is not going to happen. So it is important that you invest the time to connect, to engage and to get to know the people that are in your environment, and more importantly to give them the opportunity to know you. Because once they know you, there's a higher probability that when you approach them to ask them to be your sponsor, they will in fact answer in the affirmative. Now, if you're with me and you agree that you have to have a sponsor, let's talk about how you identify a sponsor. Well, if you're looking for a sponsor,
que es el que se genera por las inversiones que hacen en la gente de su entorno, las inversiones que hacen en la gente de su entorno. No pueden pedir a alguien que utilice su bien ganado beneplácito de popularidad personal en su nombre si nunca han interactuado con ellos. No va a pasar. Así que es importante que inviertan tiempo en conectar, en hablar y en conocer a la gente de su entorno, y lo que es más importante, darles la oportunidad de que los conozcan. Porque una vez que los conozcan, habrá una mayor probabilidad de que cuando se acerquen a ellos para pedirles que sean su promotor, respondan que sí. Si son como yo y están de acuerdo en que hay que tener un promotor, hablemos sobre cómo identificar a uno. Si están buscando un promotor
they need to have three primary characteristics. Number one, they need to have a seat at the decision-making table, they need to have exposure to your work in order to have credibility behind closed doors, and they need to have some juice, or let me say it differently, they'd better have some power. It's really important that they have those three things. And then once you have identified the person,
deben tener tres características básicas. Número uno, tienen que tener un lugar en la mesa en la que se toman decisiones, tienen que estar expuestos a su trabajo para tener credibilidad a puerta cerrada, y tienen que tener influencia, o por decirlo de otra manera, más les vale tener algo de poder. Es muy importante que tengan esas tres cosas. Y una vez que hayan identificado a esa persona,
how do you ask for one? The script goes like this. "Jim, I'm really interested in getting promoted this year. I've had an amazing year and I cannot show this organization anything else to prove my worthiness or my readiness for this promotion,
¿cómo se lo piden? El guion es algo así. "Jim, me interesa mucho que me ascendieran este año. He tenido un año increíble y no hay nada más que pueda enseñar a esta empresa para demostrar que valgo o que estoy listo para un ascenso,
but I am aware that somebody has to be behind closed doors arguing on my behalf and pounding the table. You know me, you know my work and you are aware of the client feedback, and I hope that you will feel comfortable arguing on my behalf." If Jim knows you
pero también soy consciente de que tiene que haber alguien a puerta cerrada que pelee por mi beneficio y de un golpe sobre la mesa. Me conoce, conoce mi trabajo y conoce la retroalimentación de los clientes y espero que se sienta a gusto discutiendo en mi nombre". Si Jim los conoce
and you have any kind of a relationship, there's a very high probability that he will answer yes, and if he says yes, he will endeavor to get it done for you. But there's also a shot that Jim might say no, and if he says no, in my opinion, there's only three reasons that he would tell you no. The first is he doesn't think that he has enough exposure to your work to have real credibility behind closed doors to be impactful and effective on your behalf. The second reason he may tell you no is that you think he has the juice to get it done, but he knows that he does not have the power to do it and he is not going to admit that in that conversation with you. (Laughter) And the third reason that he would tell you no, he doesn't like you. He doesn't like you. (Laughter) And that's something that could happen. But even that will be valuable information for you that will help to inform your next conversation with a sponsor that might make it a little bit more impactful. I cannot tell you how important it is to have a sponsor. It is the critical relationship in your career.
y tienen algún tipo de relación hay una probabilidad muy alta de que diga que sí, y si dice que sí, se esforzará en sacarlo adelante. Pero cabe la posibilidad de que Jim diga que no, y si dice que no, en mi opinión, solo hay tres razones por las que diría que no. La primera es que crea que no conoce su trabajo lo suficiente como para tener credibilidad real a puerta cerrada para impactar y ser efectivo en su nombre. La segunda razón por la que puede decir que no es que Uds. piensan que tiene influencia para conseguirlo, pero él sabe que no tiene poder para hacerlo y no va admitirlo delante de Uds. (Risas) Y la tercera razón por la que diría que no es que Ud. no le agrada. Ud. no le agrada. (Risas) Y eso es algo que podría pasar. Pero hasta eso sería información valiosa para Ud. que le ayudará en su siguiente conversación con un promotor y puede que le haga tener algo más de impacto. No les puedo decir lo importante que es tener un promotor. Es la relación fundamental en sus trabajos.
A mentor, frankly, is a nice to have, but you can survive a long time in your career without a mentor, but you are not going to ascend in any organization without a sponsor. It is so critical that you should ask yourself regularly, "Who's carrying my paper into the room? Who is carrying my paper into the room?" And if you can't answer who is carrying your paper into the room, then I will tell you to divert some of your hardworking energies into investing in a sponsor relationship, because it will be critical to your success. And as I close, let me give a word to the would-be sponsors that are in the room. If you have been invited into the room, know that you have a seat at that table, and if you have a seat at the table, you have a responsibility to speak. Don't waste your power worrying about what people are going to say and whether or not they think you might be supporting someone just because they look like you. If somebody is worthy of your currency, spend it. One thing I have learned after several decades on Wall Street is the way to grow your power is to give it away, and your voice is at the heart. (Applause) And your voice is at the heart of your power. Use it. Thank you very much. (Applause)
Sinceramente, es agradable tener un mentor, pero se puede sobrevivir mucho tiempo profesionalmente sin uno, pero no van a ascender en ninguna organización sin un promotor. Es tan fundamental que deberían preguntarse con frecuencia: "¿Quién va a llevar mis papeles a la sala? ¿Quién va a llevar mis papeles a la sala?". Y si no pueden contestar esa pregunta les diré que desvíen parte de su energía de su trabajo duro hacia la inversión en una relación con un promotor, porque será fundamental para su éxito. Para terminar, déjenme decirles algo a los futuros promotores que están en aquí. Si los han invitado a la sala, sepan que tienen un sitio en la mesa, y si tienen un sitio en la mesa tienen la responsabilidad de hablar. No gasten su poder preocupándose por lo que va a decir la gente o por si piensan o no que pueden estar apoyando a alguien simplemente porque son como Uds. Si alguien es digno de su beneplácito, díganlo. Una de las cosas que he aprendido tras varias décadas en Wall Street es que la manera de hacer crecer su poder es repartiéndolo y sus voces son muy importantes. (Aplausos) Sus voces son lo más importante de su poder. Úsenlas. Muchísimas gracias. (Aplausos)